<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Educational And Learning on OpenAssistive - Open source Assistive Technology Solutions</title>
    <link>https://openassistive.org/tags/educational-and-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Educational And Learning on OpenAssistive - Open source Assistive Technology Solutions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://openassistive.org/tags/educational-and-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>ACollab</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/ACollab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/ACollab/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;ACollab is available as a work groups &lt;strong&gt;addon for ATutor 1.4+&lt;/strong&gt; , and as a standalone collaborative work environment that will run on its own. ACollab is ideal for groups working at a distance developing documentation, collaborating on research, or writing joint papers, and ideal for online educators who wish to add group learning activities to their ATutor courses. A &lt;a acollab=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;&#34;&gt;demo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a acollab=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;&#34;&gt;download&lt;/a&gt; are available if you want to learn more. Or, read on for a list of &lt;a href=&#34;&#34; portal_factory=&#34;&#34;&gt;ACollab features&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;acollab-features&#34;&gt;ACollab Features:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Document Drafting Room&lt;/strong&gt;: Group members can work within a Web-based document versioning system, collaborating on document development and publication. Documents developed in the Drafting Room can be transferred to the Shared Documents Library once finalized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shared Documents Library&lt;/strong&gt;: Group members can submit documents to the library, from which other group members, or public members, can retrieve those documents for viewing or downloading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Events Calendar&lt;/strong&gt;: Events can be posted to the calendar by all group members, to announce activities, meetings, due dates, or other group related happenings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News &amp;amp; Announcements&lt;/strong&gt;: Group administrators, or system administrators, can post news to be presented to users when they first login to a group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group Membership Index&lt;/strong&gt;: Group members can view other group members&amp;rsquo; profiles and contact information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mail Inbox&lt;/strong&gt;: Members can communicate with each other privately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AChat-PHP&lt;/strong&gt;: Accessible synchronous communication is possible between group members, ideal for online meetings or group socializing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AForum&lt;/strong&gt;: AForum is an enhanced version for the ATutor forums. Members post message for others to retrieve later. Forums can be set to read only, reply only, as open discussion, or can be hidden from view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-Lingual Interface&lt;/strong&gt;: Language can be modified by system administrators, or new language packs can be created using the ATutor.ca translation tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accessibility Compliance&lt;/strong&gt;: Group member, group administrator, and system administrator tools are all compliant with international accessibility standards (WCAG 1.0, Section 508 US) so people with disabilities can participate fully in collaborative and administrative activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group Leaders&lt;/strong&gt;: Create chat transcripts, define folders for sorting documents, assign group membership roles, create and manage forums, create mailing lists, post news and announcements, and manage group members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System Administrator&lt;/strong&gt;: Create and manage groups, manage the system languages, and manage all users on a system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.atutor.ca/acollab/docs/howto.php&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.atutor.ca/acollab/index.php&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.atutor.ca/forum/16/1.html&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-atutor-ca-acollab-download-php&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.atutor.ca/acollab/download.php&#34;&gt;http://www.atutor.ca/acollab/download.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARASAAC Pictograms</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/ARASAACPictograms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/ARASAACPictograms/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-the-authors&#34;&gt;From the authors:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ARASAAC portal offers graphic resources and materials to facilitate communication for those with some sort of problem in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OATSoft comment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an increasingly popular and widely used AAC resource, and the symbol file libraries are available with the file names translated into a growing number of languages. The file format provided is 500 pixels high PNG. Though the number of files is quite large, there is a fair amount of redundancy due to numerous duplication of symbols labelled with different names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.catedu.es/arasaac/index.php&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-catedu-es-arasaac-descargas-php&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.catedu.es/arasaac/descargas.php&#34;&gt;http://www.catedu.es/arasaac/descargas.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acomm</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/Acomm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/Acomm/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;acomm-features&#34;&gt;AComm Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User can login to an existing Jabber account or sign up for a new one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roster provides &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;presence&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; information for contacts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users can participate in private or group chat/whiteboard sessions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text chat window and optional whiteboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participant list on demand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A variety of whiteboard drawing tools are available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peer description allows any participant to describe the drawn objects. Anti-collision feature ensures one describer per object.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accessibility options

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Option to play sound effect when a new message arrives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyboard drawing checkbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manual refresh checkbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show only new checkbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Newest message first checkbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyboard enabled drawing lets users use some features of the whiteboard without a mouse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save and open palette feature lets users create and describe pictures beforehand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AComm is a Java application and requires that a Java Runtime Environment be installed on system it is running on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/acomm/help&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.atutor.ca/acomm/index.php&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.atutor.ca/forums/index.php&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-atutor-ca-acomm-download-php&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.atutor.ca/acomm/download.php&#34;&gt;http://www.atutor.ca/acomm/download.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acta</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/Acta/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/Acta/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/acta/help&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a-sharp.com/acta/acta.html&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-a-sharp-com-acta-download-html&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.a-sharp.com/acta/download.html&#34;&gt;http://www.a-sharp.com/acta/download.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atutor</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/Atutor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/Atutor/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;atutor-features&#34;&gt;ATutor Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accessibility&lt;/strong&gt;: ATutor was designed with accessibility as a priority. A wide range of features ensure assistive technology users can participate fully in learner, instructor, and administrative activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Courses&lt;/strong&gt; : Instructors and students can manage the ATutor courses they teach and/or are enrolled in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adaptive Navigation&lt;/strong&gt;: Learners can move through ATutor content using global, hierarchical, or sequential navigation tools. Navigation elements can be displayed as text, icons, or both text and icons, and they can be hidden to simplify the environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work Groups&lt;/strong&gt;: When the ACollab add-on is installed on an ATutor system, learners can collaborate with others on course projects, communicate as a group with the forums and chat, share resources using their group library, schedule activities with the events calendar, and work together on project documents through the drafting room. Exercises or assignments can submitted to the group leader, or course instructor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback&lt;/strong&gt;: Following an action (such as saving preference settings, or posting a message), feedback is given on the status of the operation. This could be a success message, warnings to consider, or errors to fix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preference Settings&lt;/strong&gt;: Learners can control ATutor features and the theme ATutor is presented in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Learners can communicate with others using ATutor&amp;rsquo;s private mail, the discussion forums, the chat rooms, or the &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;User&amp;rsquo;s Online&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; tool. Threads and messages can be sorted in a variety of ways. Students can communicate with those in other courses through shared forum, or a community forum. Subscribe to forums or topic threads to have forum messages sent by email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content Package Viewer&lt;/strong&gt;: Learners can export content from ATutor as Content Packages that can be viewed offline in the accompanying viewer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content Tracker&lt;/strong&gt;: Learners can keep track of the content pages they have visited.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Test Manager&lt;/strong&gt;: Learners can take tests, review test results, and keep track of their scores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glossary&lt;/strong&gt;: Words and phrases added to the glossary by the instructor, can be accessed from terms embedded within content pages, or viewed alphabetically in their entirety using the Glossary tool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links Database&lt;/strong&gt;: Each course has a tool for collecting links to course related Web-based information. Both students and instructors can add links. Instructors can also manage them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course Search&lt;/strong&gt;: A search engine allows learners to search course content. Search for courses in the course catalogue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TILE Repository Search&lt;/strong&gt;: Learners can &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;search the TILE learning objects repository&lt;/a&gt; for content related to the topics they are studying, and download content packages for viewing offline.
Instructors&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sourceforge.net/docman/?group_id=21294&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:greggy@users.sourceforge.net&#34;&gt;Contact Address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.atutor.ca/index.php&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.atutor.ca/forums/index.php&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-atutor-ca-atutor-download-php&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.atutor.ca/atutor/download.php&#34;&gt;http://www.atutor.ca/atutor/download.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Calculator</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/BigCalculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/BigCalculator/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The size of the calculator buttons is determined by the WIDTH of the calculator window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big Calculator will use a &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;SAPI 4.0 speech&lt;/a&gt; system if you have one installed on your system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tip: for extra large read-out, set a wide, short window, and input with the numeric keys.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/big-calculator/help&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sensorysoftware.com/bigcalculator.html&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-sensorysoftware-com-bigcalculator-html&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sensorysoftware.com/bigcalculator.html&#34;&gt;http://www.sensorysoftware.com/bigcalculator.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blissymbolics Resources</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/BlissymbolicsResources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/BlissymbolicsResources/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The complete current authorised lexical resources of Blissymbolics are here available with an overview, tracked changes, lexical source text files (in the unfortunately proprietary WinBliss editor format), export file libraries (in a range of different file formats and sizes (SVG, PNG, BMP and WMF), spreadsheet and PDF lexical documentation files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Note: Registering and login is required for access to the Community Area of the Blissymbolics Communications International (BCI) site where these resources are available.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:bci@blissymbolics.org&#34;&gt;Contact Address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blissymbolics.org/&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-blissymbolics-org-community-index-php-resources&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blissymbolics.org/community/index.php/resources#&#34;&gt;http://www.blissymbolics.org/community/index.php/resources#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyday Skills</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/EverydaySkills/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/EverydaySkills/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deafblindonline.org.uk/everyday_skills_manual.doc&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deafblindonline.org.uk/&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deafblindonline.org.uk/feedback.html&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download&#34;&gt;Download:&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hark The Sound</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/HarkTheSound/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/HarkTheSound/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-the-author&#34;&gt;From the author:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-it-like&#34;&gt;What is it like?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The object of the game is to name a sound or tune that is presented as a prompt. A typical round in &lt;em&gt;Name That Animal&lt;/em&gt; goes like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You hear &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Can you name this animal?&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then an animal sound is played, for example a dog barking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You use the &lt;em&gt;left&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; arrow keys on the keyboard to move through and hear the possible answers. In this case they might be &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Cat&amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;, &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Dog&amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;, &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Elephant&amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;, and &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Horse&amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In some games, the &lt;em&gt;down&lt;/em&gt; arrow key will give a hint about the correct answer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you hear the correct answer, you press the &lt;em&gt;up&lt;/em&gt; arrow key to guess.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the chosen answer is correct, you will hear a &lt;em&gt;reward&lt;/em&gt; sound which might be a crowd cheering, or a musical fan fare. If the answer is incorrect, you will hear &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Try again.&amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The process then repeats playing another one of the sounds for the four animals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When all the animals in the group have been played, the game begins another round with four more animals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When &lt;strong&gt;Hark The Sound&lt;/strong&gt; first starts it says &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Use the left or right arrow keys to choose a game to play.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; Using the arrow keys you can move through and hear the choices for games (listed below). When you hear a game you want to play, use the &lt;em&gt;up&lt;/em&gt; arrow key to select it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Escape&lt;/em&gt; key (often labeled &lt;strong&gt;ESC&lt;/strong&gt; in the upper left corner of the keyboard) will quit the current game and return to the game selections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-games-are-available&#34;&gt;What games are available?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the games follow the same general pattern as described above of Question, Prompt, Answers, Reward. Games that ship with version 1.2 of &lt;strong&gt;Hark The Sound&lt;/strong&gt; include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Braille Letters: The question is &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Can you name this Braille letter?&amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;. The prompts are the dots of a letter. The answers are the letter along with a word that begins with that letter to make it easier to hear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Braille Whole Word Contractions: The question is &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Can you name this Braille whole word contraction?&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; The prompts are the dots in a Braille letter that is a whole word contraction. The word is the answer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Counting: Counting repeated animal sounds for numbers one through nine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiplication drills: The full multiplication table up to 12 times 12. The question is &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;What is this product?&amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;. The prompts are products like &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;2 times 3&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; and the answers are numbers from 0 through 144.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name That Animal: Animal sounds are the prompts. The animal&amp;rsquo;s names are the answers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name that capital&amp;rsquo;s State: A challenging game of State Capitals. The question is &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Can you name the state whose capital is&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;, the prompts are the names of capital cities. The answers are the names of the 50 states.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name that Classical Tune: Midi versions of famous classical music are the prompts. The composer&amp;rsquo;s name and the name of the work are included in the answer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name that color: The question is &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;What color is this?&amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;, the prompts are common objects, and the answers are their colors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name That Country Music Tune: Country music classics rendered in Midi. Composer and name are the answer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name that holiday: Identify holidays from hints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name that Kids Tune: Midi tunes like &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Head Shoulders Knees and Toes&amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name that Rock and Roll Tune: Classic rock and roll tunes rendered in Midi with the artist and title for the answer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name that Sound: Environmental sounds, such as &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;clock ticking&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;glass breaking&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; are the prompts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spelling Words: The prompt is a word spelled out. The answer is the word pronounced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;State Nick Names: A challenging game to identify the nick name for a state given its name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/hark-the-sound/help&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.unc.edu/Research/assist/Hark/index.html&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-cs-unc-edu-gb-research-hark-the-sound-install-instructions-html&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.unc.edu/~gb/research/hark-the-sound/install-instructions.html&#34;&gt;http://www.cs.unc.edu/~gb/research/hark-the-sound/install-instructions.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inclusive CD Player</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/InclusiveCDPlayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/InclusiveCDPlayer/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inclusive.co.uk/downloads/inc_cd_readme.doc&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inclusive.co.uk/downloads/downloads.shtml#cdplayer&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-inclusive-co-uk-downloads-inclusive-cd-player-exe&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inclusive.co.uk/downloads/Inclusive_CD_Player.exe&#34;&gt;http://www.inclusive.co.uk/downloads/Inclusive_CD_Player.exe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launcher6</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/Launcher6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/Launcher6/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;meta charset=&#34;windows-1252&#34;&#34;&#34; content=&#34;&#34; content-type=&#34;&#34; http-equiv=&#34;&#34; text=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/meta&gt;&lt;meta content=&#34;&#34; generator=&#34;&#34; microsoft=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;&#34; word=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/meta&gt;&lt;title&gt;Launcher Help Information:&lt;/title&gt;&lt;meta c:=&#34;&#34; content=&#34;&#34; files=&#34;&#34; name=&#34;&#34; office=&#34;&#34; template=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/meta&gt;Launcher Help Information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Launcher6&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launcher6 is a simple interface for launching programs, a simple electronic speech aid, or a multimedia game spinner! And, best of all, it&amp;rsquo;s freeware. Launcher6 covers the screen providing users with a restricted environment, allowing choices, but reducing the probability that the user will access the usual, and perhaps troublesome, Windows interface. It supports access using single switch, two switch, Intellikeys, touch screen and mouse methods. Facilitators can configure the six cells on the launcher6 screen using the built-in editor. Launcher6 continually saves this &amp;lsquo;setup&amp;rsquo; as changes occur in a text file that ends with a &amp;lsquo;.ls6&amp;rsquo; extention. Each cell within a setup can be assigned the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A graphic element of types: &amp;lsquo;.bmp&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;.jpg&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;.gif&amp;rsquo; (animation is ok), or &amp;lsquo;.png&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A cue either as a sound file or as text to be spoken via a clipboard text to speech utility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A message in the same way as the cue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A registered filetype or a program to open.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A link to another launcher6 setup.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;An action: hide me, show all, quit, or none.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When launcher6 starts it always loads the settings saved in the file &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;main.ls6&amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;. From the &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;main&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; setup you can link to other setups. The &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;main.ls6&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; setup must be in the same directory as the &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;launcher6.exe&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; program file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Launcher6 has support for the following access methods&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mouse or touchscreen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don Johsnton (or equivalent) switch interface&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;keyboard devices (like Intellikeys)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Launcher6 responds to the following keys&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;@&lt;/strong&gt; = Disable/Enable the following keyboard commands, enabled by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;= Start/Stop autoscan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; = Highlight the next cell for 2 switch scan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; = Select highlighted item for 2 switch scan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; = Spin selects a random cell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;q&lt;/strong&gt; = quit launcher6&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;e&lt;/strong&gt; = edit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;z&lt;/strong&gt; = resize screen smaller&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;f&lt;/strong&gt; = resize screen to full screen dimensions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;t,y,u,i,o,p&lt;/strong&gt; = direct access to cells 1,2,3,4,5,6 respectively in left to right, top to bottom order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;h&lt;/strong&gt; = help&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;m&lt;/strong&gt; = Go to the &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;main.ls6&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; setup&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Use Mouse Scan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is set to true in the editor Launcher6 will use left mouse click to start and stop scanning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;General Settings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following settings at the bottom of the Editor (type &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;e&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; from the lauuncher6 screen.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scan Rate&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set the scan rate in seconds for single switch scanners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get/Name Setup&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can either save the current setup under a new name, or load a previously saved setup. For convenience, keep all the setup files (*.ls6 files) in the same folder as launcher6.exe. Unfortunately, if you move launcher6 to another computer, the links to various resources are not likely to work, and you may need to rebuild your setups. It is a good idea to save a blank, or partially completed common setup that you can use as a template for new named setups to reduce work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to build a new setup and set links to it&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open the editor (type &amp;lsquo;e&amp;rsquo; while in the launcher6 screen) and use the Get/Name Setup button to name a new setup.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit the cells on the newly named setup.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open other setup(s) and edit cell links to the newly named setup as desired.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Mouse Scan&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If set to true, the left mouse click will initiate an auto (single switch scan) scan in the launcher screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speech Output&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose either Use Sound Files or Use Clipboard Text to Speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you choose sound files, then the definitions for Cues and Messages should be paths to sound files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you choose text-to-speech, then the cues and messages are defined as simple text. Text-to- speech is provided by an external program that converts text sent to the &amp;lsquo;clipboard&amp;rsquo; to speech sounds. The programs &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;SayzMe&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;DeskBot&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; are good choices. Both programs are easily obtained on the Internet, and both require the Microsoft Agent to be installed. As a convenience, specify a cell on the main setup, or some other setup that launches your preferred clipboard text-to-speech utility. Or, launch your text-to-speech utility at startup. Make sure you turn off unnecessary sounds or character animations that may detract from a clear auditory scan. Refer to the settings of those programs for selecting voices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ãƒâ€šÃ‚Â &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editing Cell Settings:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Type &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;e&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; from launcher6 to open editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editing Cell&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This box indicates which of the six launcher6 cells setup details are shown. Use the up and dn buttons to change which cell is referenced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set Pic&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This button asks you to locate a picture file for the cell indicated in the &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Editing Cell&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; box above. Avoid using pictures that have large invisible areas that may make it difficult for mouse or touscreen users to select.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set Cue&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This button asks you to either locate a sound file for an auditory scanning cue, or to enter some text if Use Clipboard Speech has been selected (See General Settings).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set Message&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This button asks you to either locate a sound file for a message when the cell is selected, or to enter some text if Use Clipboard Speech (See General Settings).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find a File to Open&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This button asks you to find a program to launch, or registered file to open. Most executable program files will launch without problems. However, with registered filetypes Launcher6 edits the filepath to make it compatible with DOS. This means file and folder names will be truncated to adhere to the DOS 8.3 format. Filenames longer than 8 letters will be reduced to 6 letters followed by &amp;lsquo;~1&amp;rsquo;. Spaces in names are not allowed. This option doesn&amp;rsquo;t always work. If after attempting to open your choice with the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Test It&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; button (which always gives you a little lecture) it doesn&amp;rsquo;t open, move your target file to another location, or rename it, and try again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can identify either a file to open, or identify another launcher6 setup to load as described next, but not both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set Link to Another Launcher Page&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This button asks you to identify another launcher6 setup file (somefile.ls6) to load.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can identify either a file to open as described above, or another launcher6 setup, but not both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Define Action&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This button asks you to select from the following actions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hide me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; hides the target button when selected&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Show all&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; Show all hidden buttons&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;End Session&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; Closes launcher6&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;None&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash;- Does nothing, and is the default action&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;lsquo;hide me&amp;rsquo; action can be used to allow a target cell to be used only once per session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/launcher6/help&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jamjolu@hotmail.com&#34;&gt;Contact Address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sites.google.com/site/jamjolu/Home/launcher6&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-sites-google-com-site-jamjolu-home-launcher6&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://sites.google.com/site/jamjolu/Home/launcher6&#34;&gt;http://sites.google.com/site/jamjolu/Home/launcher6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MQA Spell Checker</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/MQASpellChecker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/MQASpellChecker/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-the-authors-say&#34;&gt;What the authors say:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spell Checker checks the spelling of any edit control in almost any application under Windows 3.1/95/98. The program was designed to run under Windows 3.1. Though it will operate under Windows &lt;sup&gt;95&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;98&lt;/sub&gt;, it is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;not compatible with&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; later versions (2000, ME, XP). It runs in the background and is brought into use in any edit window by pressing a hot-key combination. Master dictionaries are available in several languages and fully editable and searchable custom dictionaries can be created. The system requirements are modest and it should run on any computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/MQASpellChecker/help&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:mqa@quinion.com&#34;&gt;Contact Address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quinion.com/mqa/spell.htm&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-quinion-com-mqa-spell-htm&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quinion.com/mqa/spell.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.quinion.com/mqa/spell.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Reader</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/MicrosoftReader/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/MicrosoftReader/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;You must have Microsoft Reader installed on your machine before the Microsoft Reader Text-to-Speech Package can be installed. The Text-to-Speech Package is available in English, French and German.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;oats-comment&#34;&gt;OATS Comment:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be great for people who want to either:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read books but can&amp;rsquo;t turn pages (use in conjunction with a switch-input program)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read books but struggle to see the text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Need some support in reading text (e.g. highlighting)

&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/reader/info/default.asp&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/reader/default.asp&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-microsoft-com-reader-downloads-pc-aspx&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/reader/downloads/pc.aspx&#34;&gt;http://www.microsoft.com/reader/downloads/pc.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mulberry symbol set</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/Mulberrysymbolset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/Mulberrysymbolset/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Working locally in Essex, UK. our software is free, but in the past we always had to purchase commercial symbol sets to accompany our products. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a fully funded project to develop the Mulberry Symbol Set.  It will be free of cost to everyone and distributed with a Creative Commons BY-SA license (essentially making these images &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;open source&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; -  that is, the user will be free to copy, distribute or amend these images as they see fit).   You will be able to use them with any software that supports .wmf format.   This includes, with permission, commercial products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A team of people are now producing symbols with 2500 now available with a further 1000 in production. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to publishing each new batch of symbols, they are reviewed by a team of professionals (such as speech and language therapists, teachers and classroom assistants and representatives from suppliers of AAC devices).    If you would like to join the team of people who review these symbols, please let us know at &lt;a href=&#34;&#34; mailto:support=&#34;&#34;&gt;support@straight-street.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;                       &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/straight-street-symbol-set/help&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:support@straight-street.com&#34;&gt;Contact Address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.straight-street.com/&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-straight-street-com&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.straight-street.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.straight-street.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Games</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/MusicGames/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/MusicGames/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inclusive.co.uk/downloads/music_games.pdf&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inclusive.co.uk/downloads/downloads.shtml#musicgames&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-inclusive-co-uk-downloads-downloads-shtml-musicgames&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inclusive.co.uk/downloads/downloads.shtml#musicgames&#34;&gt;http://www.inclusive.co.uk/downloads/downloads.shtml#musicgames&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>