<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Symbols on OpenAssistive - Open source Assistive Technology Solutions</title>
    <link>https://openassistive.org/tags/symbols/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Symbols on OpenAssistive - Open source Assistive Technology Solutions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://openassistive.org/tags/symbols/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>ARASAAC Pictograms</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/ARASAACPictograms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/ARASAACPictograms/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-the-authors&#34;&gt;From the authors:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ARASAAC portal offers graphic resources and materials to facilitate communication for those with some sort of problem in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OATSoft comment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an increasingly popular and widely used AAC resource, and the symbol file libraries are available with the file names translated into a growing number of languages. The file format provided is 500 pixels high PNG. Though the number of files is quite large, there is a fair amount of redundancy due to numerous duplication of symbols labelled with different names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.catedu.es/arasaac/index.php&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-catedu-es-arasaac-descargas-php&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.catedu.es/arasaac/descargas.php&#34;&gt;http://www.catedu.es/arasaac/descargas.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blissymbolics Resources</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/BlissymbolicsResources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/BlissymbolicsResources/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The complete current authorised lexical resources of Blissymbolics are here available with an overview, tracked changes, lexical source text files (in the unfortunately proprietary WinBliss editor format), export file libraries (in a range of different file formats and sizes (SVG, PNG, BMP and WMF), spreadsheet and PDF lexical documentation files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Note: Registering and login is required for access to the Community Area of the Blissymbolics Communications International (BCI) site where these resources are available.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:bci@blissymbolics.org&#34;&gt;Contact Address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blissymbolics.org/&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-blissymbolics-org-community-index-php-resources&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blissymbolics.org/community/index.php/resources#&#34;&gt;http://www.blissymbolics.org/community/index.php/resources#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concept Coding Framework (CCF)</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/ConceptCodingFramework%28CCF%29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/ConceptCodingFramework%28CCF%29/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;news&#34;&gt;News&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-february-2011-mats-lundälv&#34;&gt;3 February 2011 - (Mats Lundälv)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In spite of nothing appearing at this spot for quite some time, the CCF development continues, currently in the context of the AEGIS project. More to appear here soon after the recent move of the server home of OATS, as well as for the conceptcoding.org domain. More to come - soon hopefully &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-september-2009-mats-lundälv&#34;&gt;3 September 2009 - (Mats Lundälv)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The summer has passed and the work towards the first CCF release is slowly progressing. Will we make it during the 3rd quarter of 2009 as envisaged ? Well - surprise - possibly not :-/ It currently looks uncertain whether we will be ready during this month. It will probably be a bit later this autumn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bengt Farre&amp;rsquo;s completely re-written new SYMBERED version is getting close to completion, but still has some way to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that Lars Nordberg is well on the way to transfer our CCF databases from MySQL to the &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Sun JavaDB&lt;/a&gt; (based on &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Apache Derby&lt;/a&gt;) Java database. This will provide another option for providing CCF resources (in addition to the MySQL and RDF resources) in a light weight format that will be easier to deploy, install and use for those who will like to try working with CCF based applications and services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll keep you updated at this space ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;19-june-2009-mats-lundälv&#34;&gt;19 June 2009 - (Mats Lundälv)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A first full release of the updated CCF package is now envisaged during the 3rd quarter of 2009. It will cover a set of concepts covering the authorized Blissymbolics vocabulary of around 4450 Bliss-words. These will be organised in a Base Reference Ontology (BRO) with concepts covered by WordNet, and a Complementary Reference Ontology (CRO) for the rest. The Concept Coded concepts in the Reference Ontologies will be linked to an open ended numbers of so called Assistive Ontologies containing the different supported language representations for the concepts - Bliss being the first target for graphical symbol representations, and English and Swedish being the first natural language lexicons fully supported. The structure is already prepared for supporting a number of other symbolic representations, as well as all Scandinavian/Nordic, and a number of other European languages. More will be added as soon as interest and resources will be around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In technical terms; the first release will contain a Java based CCF Tool for browsing and managing the CCF resources (&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;WordNet&lt;/a&gt;, the BRO and CRO, Assistive Ontologies and symbol resources). The data will be stored in or retrieved from either a MySQL database or an RDF/XML based resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first practical implementation will be an updated version of the &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;SYMBERED&lt;/a&gt; tool for creating symbol supported web content via a CMS module written in PHP working towards the MySQL database. (This will be a complete re-write of the first SYMBERED version based on the &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Papunet &lt;/a&gt;CMS). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next practical implementation will be the first prototypes of the envisaged CCF symbol support plugin extension for OpenOffice.org within the AEGIS project - planned for the 4th quarter of 2009.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;08-june-2009-mats-lundälv&#34;&gt;08 June 2009 - (Mats Lundälv)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the AEGIS project 1:st international workshop (in Slough at RIM 05 June) Dr. Christian Galinski from &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Infoterm &lt;/a&gt;gave a very interesting and informative presentation on issues concerning &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Standards for content in the field of eInclusion - and beyond&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; - with great relevance for the CCF work in particular, and for the &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;AEGIS &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Raising The Floor&lt;/a&gt; projects in general. We will have to do some studying about ISO//TC 37 &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Terminology and other language and content resources&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; ;-)  I hope the presentations will be on-line soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;22-february-2009-mats-lundälv&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22 February 2009 - (Mats Lundälv)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The  concept coding work has continued in slow pace as follow up work after the Nordic &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;SYMBERED project&lt;/a&gt; - which is still ongoing.&lt;br /&gt;
It is now brought further in relation to a task within the ongoing European and international &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;AEGIS-project&lt;/a&gt;. Concept coding will be employed in building open source components for graphic symbol support - in OpenOffice.org, as well as in prototype Java based cross-platform AAC applications - for mobile devices and other environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;03-12-2007-andy-judson&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03/12/2007 - (Andy Judson)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my move from the University of Dundee&amp;rsquo;s School of Computing, I thought it time I ported the old CCF website to the OATS portal. With the Bliss Think Tank in July&amp;rsquo;07 we&amp;rsquo;ve been busy hacking more demonstrators. Mats, Bengt and Lars have been busy fine-tuning the &lt;a coding=&#34;&#34; concept=&#34;&#34; editor=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;&#34; symbered=&#34;&#34; symbol=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;SYMBERED&lt;/a&gt; system (CCF support for CMS - using PHP, MySQL, Java). I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy working on a .NET infrastructure and building a central CCF ontology in SQLServer. The database I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with is now populated with around 9000 concepts (based on the STANDUP project ontology) and around 3000 Bliss symbols (some of which are mapped to concept codes). There is an prototype asp.net website where you can search the ontologies, update the bliss-ccf mappings, write ruby annotated bliss messages (then you can copy the source to your own website like I&amp;rsquo;ve done below). This webservice could be used as a portal to manage the ccf, and more excitingly, for use by other software / web applications, e.g. &lt;a foxysymbols=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;FoxySymbols&lt;/a&gt;. I hope to get the webservice &amp;amp; database hosted soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around the world, people with impaired communication, including difficulties to read or write, may use symbols as an alternative or complement to character based texts. Referencing to, and exchanging these alternatively coded messages over the Internet is difficult due to the lack of standardised encoding schemes and common practises. This site is intended to motivate, describe and promote the introduction and adoption of a common, open and vendor neutral Concept Coding Framework (CCF) to overcome some of these difficulties. In particular will act as a base for all contribution to this work - be it formal documentation or informal discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The suggested CCF has been carefully designed to be conformant to the standard language technologies that are rapidly developing and penetrating the Internet communities. In this way we believe that the proposed CCF can contribute to a major leap in bridging between different technologies and products developed for AAC users and, more importantly, between these Assistive Technologies (AT) and the main-stream technologies of today&amp;rsquo;s and tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s networked information society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bridging approach also implies that the CCF is not intended to replace and exclude the use and development of current and future proprietary assistive technologies in the AAC field. Instead the CCF and its bridging technology and tools are designed to provide added value for all stake-holders; AAC users, special product developers and service providers, as well as general service and information providers who want to support improved accessibility to their products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designed to be used over the Internet for email, web-based activities, chat and/or other emerging Internet based services, the CCF technology can, however, be used by software manufacturers also to provide additional functionality, enhanced support for, and integration of, software and systems with multi-modal language features mainly intended for local use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although, this work is part of the EU funded WWAAC project, the concept coding work is to be kept open source as we want to collaborate with experts and stakeholders in both the AAC field and internet technologies/accessibility area. Thus we are wanting to use this area to establish an interest group in the concept coding approach. if you are interested in getting involved at whatever level then please contact us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are some of the most relevant links i can think of to share, if you have others, please add them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;research-projects&#34;&gt;research projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;wwaac&lt;/a&gt; project (the eu project that funded this initial work)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;&#34; left=&#34;&#34;&gt;- &#34;&#34;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Code ofPractice&lt;/a&gt;&#34;&#34; - the WWAAC project deliverable on the Concept Coding Framework (PDF 1.2MB)

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;symbered&lt;/a&gt; project (swedish project continuing ccf developments)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;swad-europe&lt;/a&gt; project (semantic web advanced development for europe)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;web-accessibility-resources-general&#34;&gt;web accessibility resources (general)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;w3c-wai&lt;/a&gt; (world wide web consortium - web accessibility initiative)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;w3c-wcag&lt;/a&gt; (world wide web consortium - web content accessibility guidelines working group)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;w3c-wcag 1.0&lt;/a&gt; (world wide web consortium - web content accessibility guidelines 1.0)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;w3c-wcag 2.0 (draft)&lt;/a&gt; (world wide web consortium - web content accessibility guidelines 2.0)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;w3c-wcag 2.0 rdf techniques (draft)&lt;/a&gt; (rdf techniques document for wcag 2.0 (above))&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;dmag&lt;/a&gt; (digital media access group)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;accessify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;alistapart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;diveintoaccessibility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;jakob nielsen on usability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;web-accessibility-resources-learning-difficulties&#34;&gt;web accessibility resources (learning difficulties)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;ld-web&lt;/a&gt; (web specialists looking into learning difficulties)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;juicystudio article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;webusability article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;article by lisa seeman at www2002 conference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;article by kanta jiwnani&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;webaim article (part1)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;webaim article (part2)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;uk leading learning difficulties charity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;communicate:webwide&lt;/a&gt; (a commercial symbol browser by widget, an leading AAC company)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technologies&#34;&gt;technologies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;rdf&lt;/a&gt; (resource description framework)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;owl&lt;/a&gt; (ontology web language)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;miscellaneous&#34;&gt;miscellaneous&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;semantic web&lt;/a&gt; (a portal to information about the semantic web)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;isaac&lt;/a&gt; (the international society for augmentative and alternative communication)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links-1&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/concept-coding-framework-ccf/help&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:Bengt.Farre@gmail.com&#34;&gt;Contact Address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.conceptcoding.org/&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-conceptcoding-org-downloads&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.conceptcoding.org/downloads&#34;&gt;http://www.conceptcoding.org/downloads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EdWord and EdWeb</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/EdWordandEdWeb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/EdWordandEdWeb/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deafblindonline.org.uk/software.html#ee&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:Paul.Blenkhorn@manchester.ac.uk&#34;&gt;Contact Address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deafblindonline.org.uk/&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-oatsoft-org-software-edword-and-edweb-downloads-2-0-0-1-sense-edword-edweb-setup-exe-warning-possible-dead-link&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/edword-and-edweb/downloads/2.0.0.1/Sense_EdWord-EdWeb_setup.exe&#34;&gt;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/edword-and-edweb/downloads/2.0.0.1/Sense_EdWord-EdWeb_setup.exe&lt;/a&gt; (Warning: possible dead-link)&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FoxySymbols</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/FoxySymbols/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/FoxySymbols/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/foxysymbols/help&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:andy.judson@gmail.com&#34;&gt;Contact Address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download&#34;&gt;Download:&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mulberry symbol set</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/Mulberrysymbolset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/Mulberrysymbolset/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Working locally in Essex, UK. our software is free, but in the past we always had to purchase commercial symbol sets to accompany our products. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a fully funded project to develop the Mulberry Symbol Set.  It will be free of cost to everyone and distributed with a Creative Commons BY-SA license (essentially making these images &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;open source&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; -  that is, the user will be free to copy, distribute or amend these images as they see fit).   You will be able to use them with any software that supports .wmf format.   This includes, with permission, commercial products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A team of people are now producing symbols with 2500 now available with a further 1000 in production. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to publishing each new batch of symbols, they are reviewed by a team of professionals (such as speech and language therapists, teachers and classroom assistants and representatives from suppliers of AAC devices).    If you would like to join the team of people who review these symbols, please let us know at &lt;a href=&#34;&#34; mailto:support=&#34;&#34;&gt;support@straight-street.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;                       &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/straight-street-symbol-set/help&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:support@straight-street.com&#34;&gt;Contact Address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.straight-street.com/&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-straight-street-com&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.straight-street.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.straight-street.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plaphoons</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/Plaphoons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/Plaphoons/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lagares.org/&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-xtec-cat-jlagares-eduespe-htm-plaphoons&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xtec.cat/~jlagares/eduespe.htm#PLAPHOONS&#34;&gt;http://www.xtec.cat/~jlagares/eduespe.htm#PLAPHOONS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power Reader</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/PowerReader/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/PowerReader/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The dyslexic community accounts for 15-20% of the U.S. population. Our goal is to build a dyslexic text reader/learning tool, a graphical, interactive text reader integrated with computer text-to-speech whose level of focus, complexity, and detail is adjustable according to the user&amp;rsquo;s needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, a multiple &amp;lsquo;level of detail&amp;rsquo; presentation of text where items can be viewed at the letter, word, sentence, and paragraph level, allowing the user needs to adjust it to their needs. Items can grow or shrink in size as they are read by the software, and the color of the text can also be adjusted. Image representations and dictionary definitions of words can be displayed next to the word as each word is read. A speech API (Free-TTS) reads each word that has the current focus, and the user can adjust the speed the text is read through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project idea was originally submitted by a dyslexic lady and developed within a &lt;a _blank=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;&#34; target=&#34;&#34;&gt;user interface course&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Southern California.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoomable User Interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactive paragraph/sentence/word selection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration with Google Images, Flickr, and Yahoo Images for image lookup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration with Wiktionary, WordNet Dictionary for dictionary definition lookup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-issues&#34;&gt;Current Issues&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not OS X friendly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Threading issues needs to be resolved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Occassional Crashes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;future-plans&#34;&gt;Future Plans&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expand number of input formats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:info@projectpossibility.org&#34;&gt;Contact Address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.projectpossibility.org/viewProject.php?id=1&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lists.projectpossibility.org/listinfo.cgi/project-powerreader-projectpossibility.org&#34;&gt;Report A Problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lists.projectpossibility.org/listinfo.cgi/project-powerreader-projectpossibility.org&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-code-google-com-p-pp-power-reader-downloads-list&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/pp-power-reader/downloads/list&#34;&gt;http://code.google.com/p/pp-power-reader/downloads/list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAW Resources</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/SAWResources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/SAWResources/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:colven@ace-centre.org.uk&#34;&gt;Contact Address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-oatsoft-org-software-saw-resources-downloads-2-6-saw-6-pdf-warning-possible-dead-link&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/saw-resources/downloads/2.6/SAW_6.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/saw-resources/downloads/2.6/SAW_6.pdf&lt;/a&gt; (Warning: possible dead-link)&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sclera&#39;s Pictos</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/Sclera%27sPictos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/Sclera%27sPictos/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-the-authors&#34;&gt;From the authors:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pictograms available for download here are originally ment to offer structure and clairity to people with a mental disability. Other applications are neither excluded nor forbidden. The use of the pictogram is confined solely by the limit of your imagination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be careful however not to over-visualise. This may reduce growing possibilities. Sometimes if we put a little more effort and energy into it, we can help someone learn something without the use of pictograms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When looking at the pictograms, you may have thought some to be more or less obvious then others. You would have thought correctly. Dont&amp;rsquo;t forget that the meaning of a pictogram is what you want it to mean. The meaning of the symbol has to be learned, like you would words of a language. Imagin consequently calling a cat a dog when talking with a child. It would know no better than to call a cat a dog. We are not born with a pictogram instinct for recognition! This also means that names and meanings of the pictograms offerde here are not definite and may be changed if you want to. I can only build on my experiences and simply offer suggestions. Feel free to make changes if they are needed or are desireable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you look for a pictogram, you will sometimes find more than one version for a certain concept or word. We don&amp;rsquo;t aim to be a system understandable by everyone. We aim to provide the best fit for your personal needs. You can choose whatever version is best understood in your family or in your institution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another ground rule of Sclera Picto&amp;rsquo;s is that the pictograms are free of all charge. You can download every single pictogram at no cost. Other pictogram libraries may be more developed, but require a fee. I want to break with the notion that adjustments within caregiving always come with a price tag. I&amp;rsquo;ve committed myself to answering questions and designing other pictograms when people need them. I&amp;rsquo;d even be glad to help. But please remember the service I offer, is offered in my spare time. I may not be able to respond immediately sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/sclera-s-pictos/help&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:picto@sclera.be&#34;&gt;Contact Address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sclera.be/&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-sclera-be-index-php-page-download&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sclera.be/index.php?page=download&#34;&gt;http://www.sclera.be/index.php?page=download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Special Access To Windows</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/SpecialAccessToWindows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/SpecialAccessToWindows/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ace-centre.org.uk/index.cfm?pageid=2989F7F8-3048-7290-FE1727AA17BB7C5F&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/SpecialAccessToWindows/&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oatsoft.org/trac/saw&#34;&gt;Report A Problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-sourceforge-net-projects-sawat&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://sourceforge.net/projects/sawat/&#34;&gt;http://sourceforge.net/projects/sawat/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SymVoc</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/SymVoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/SymVoc/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Symbols in the screenshot are just an example - contents can be fully configured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More info and walk-through demos here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://symvoc.googlepages.com/documentation&#34;&gt;http://symvoc.googlepages.com/documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://symvoc.googlepages.com/documentation&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:robert.wk@gmail.com&#34;&gt;Contact Address&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://symvoc.googlepages.com/&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-symvoc-googlepages-com-download&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://symvoc.googlepages.com/download&#34;&gt;http://symvoc.googlepages.com/download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symbol &amp;amp; Concept Coding Editor (aka SYMBERED)</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/Symbol&amp;amp;ConceptCodingEditor%28akaSYMBERED%29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/Symbol&amp;amp;ConceptCodingEditor%28akaSYMBERED%29/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/SymBeRed/help&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.symbolnet.org/&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download&#34;&gt;Download:&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symbol Set Maker</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/SymbolSetMaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/SymbolSetMaker/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deafblindonline.org.uk/Symbol_Set_Wizard_manual.doc&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deafblindonline.org.uk/&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deafblindonline.org.uk/feedback.html&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-www-oatsoft-org-software-symbol-set-maker-downloads-1-0-sense-symbolsetmaker-setup-exe-warning-possible-dead-link&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/symbol-set-maker/downloads/1.0/Sense_SymbolSetMaker_setup.exe&#34;&gt;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/symbol-set-maker/downloads/1.0/Sense_SymbolSetMaker_setup.exe&lt;/a&gt; (Warning: possible dead-link)&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Desktop Project</title>
      <link>https://openassistive.org/item/TangoDesktopProject/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openassistive.org/item/TangoDesktopProject/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;While the look and feel of an application is determined by many individual components, some organization is necessary in order to unify the appearance and structure of individual icon sets used within those components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tango Desktop Project defines an &lt;a guidelines=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;&#34; icon=&#34;&#34; tango=&#34;&#34; theme=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;icon style guideline&lt;/a&gt; to which artists and designers can adhere. Work has begun with the creation of a new &lt;a href=&#34;&#34; icon=&#34;&#34; library=&#34;&#34; tango=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;icon theme&lt;/a&gt; based upon a standardized &lt;a href=&#34;&#34; icon=&#34;&#34; naming=&#34;&#34; specification=&#34;&#34; standard=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;icon naming specification&lt;/a&gt;. In addition, the project provides transitional utilities to assist in creating icon themes for existing desktop environments, such as &lt;a class=&#34;&#34; external=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; nofollow=&#34;&#34; rel=&#34;&#34; text=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;GNOME&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;&#34; external=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;&#34; http:=&#34;&#34; nofollow=&#34;&#34; rel=&#34;&#34; text=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;KDE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the Tango Desktop Project will provide the following initiatives:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A suggested default native look.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A subsystem to help standardize toolkits on a common icon naming structure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A complete set of application, mimetype, and stock &lt;a href=&#34;&#34; icon=&#34;&#34; library=&#34;&#34; tango=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;icons&lt;/a&gt; designed using a defined &lt;a guidelines=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;&#34; icon=&#34;&#34; tango=&#34;&#34; theme=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;style guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A general, cross-desktop human interface guideline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oatsoft.org/Software/tango-desktop-project/help&#34;&gt;Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tango.freedesktop.org/Tango_Desktop_Project&#34;&gt;Project Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;download-http-tango-freedesktop-org-tango-icon-library-download&#34;&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tango.freedesktop.org/Tango_Icon_Library#Download&#34;&gt;http://tango.freedesktop.org/Tango_Icon_Library#Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>